Prajit Kumar Das

Engineering Manager

(410) 370-3743

prajitdas AT gmail DOT com in linkedin.com/in/prajitdas ⊕ prajitdas.github.io

Engineering Manager seeking Senior Leadership roles. With fifteen years of experience working on large and complex software systems. Ability to lead with emotional intelligence, capable of coaching and mentoring, motivating, and team building. Achievement-oriented, adaptable, and organizationally aware manager, passionate about delivering products with significant customer impact.

SKILLS

Management – Product Management, Mentoring Software Developers and Technical Product Managers and Technical Product Owners, Cross-functional team collaboration, Agile product development

 ${\sf Domain-SAML2~SSO,~MFA,~Duo~2FA,~RBAC,~ABAC,~IAM,~Cybersecurity,~Mobile~Privacy,~and~Security}$

Platforms and tools – Linux, Android, proprietary automation platforms, IntelliJ Suite, VSCode, Git

Languages – Java, Python, Go, Unix Shell

Full-stack – MySQL, MariaDB, NoSQL, ReactJS, CSS, PHP, Bootstrap, HTML5

WORK EXPERIENCE

Engineering Manager @ Cisco Systems Inc., USA

Oct 2021 – Present

- I manage a team of Software Developers, Contractors, Technical Product Managers and Technical Product Owners in Cisco's Security Business Group.
- I lead the design, development, automated testing, and continuous integration of software security solutions for Cisco's product portfolio.
- I collaborate and coordinate with several teams working across multiple product areas and cross-functional activities to build the next generation of firewalls.
- I have delivered features for Identity and Access Management, Network Configuration Management, REST API Framework, and Cloud Services Integration.
- I ensure that Cisco's software solutions comply with our product security baselines.
- I work on the g11n internationalization of our software to increase Cisco products' market outreach.

Technical Product Manager @ Cisco Systems Inc., USA

Jan 2019 - Sep 2021

- Led the development of the key feature of Single Sign-on using SAML2.
- Helped bring in \$11 million in revenue by delivering high-priority customer requests quickly.

Software Engineer @ Cisco Systems Inc., USA

Doctorate in Computer Science, UMBC, USA

Bachelor's in Information Technology, JU, India

Sep 2017 - Dec 2018

2010 - 2017

2003 - 2007

• Worked on designing, developing, and testing software solutions for Cisco's product portfolio.

Cybersecurity Researcher @ Ebiquity Research Group, USA	Aug 2012 – Aug 2017
Built context-dependent access control solutions using Semantic Web technologies.	
Mobile Privacy Researcher @ Samsung Research America, USA • Created access control systems protecting users' data privacy through obfuscated data.	Summer 2014
Ph.D. Intern @ Apple Inc., USA • Using data analytics identified areas of accuracy improvement for Apple's Siri.	Summer 2013
Intern @ Symantec Corp., USA • Developed web solutions for automated testing of Symantec products.	Summer 2011, 2012
Software Engineer @ TCS, India • Developed API clients and carried out ETL operations using PL/SQL.	Sep 2007 – Apr 2010
EDUCATION	